SIINN CHE

191 W. Woodruff Ave. Columbus, OH, 43201 / 510-967-5152 / siinn.che@cern.ch

github: github.com/siinn / linkedin: linkedin.com/in/siinn-che

OBJECTIVE

Ph.D. student in Physics with extensive experience in large experiment data from CERN. Expert in programming with +5 years of experience in Ph.D. projects. Strong mathematics and statistics background from U.C Berkeley with B.A in Mathematics. Enjoy working in collaborative environment with a team of +10 scientists. I become passionate in data science, machine learning, and big data. With my quantitative skills, intellect and training, I wish to make a positive impact in data science.

EDUCATION

Ph.D.	Experimental Particle Physics, The Ohio State University	2014 - 2017
	"Search for Long-lived Neutral Massive Particle with Displaced dilepton Resonance at the LHC"	
M.S.	Experimental Particle Physics, The Ohio State University ("Higgs Boson as a Tool for Discovery at the LHC")	2012 - 2014
B.A.	University of California, Berkeley, Mathematics & Physics,	2007 - 2011
	Academic Achievement Scholarship Award, 2008, Linear Algebra (A+), Computational Physics (A)	

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CERN (The European Organization for Nuclear Research)

Geneva, Switzerland, 2014 - 2017

- Processed and analyzed large (~200 TB) experiment data from CERN with reduction rate < 5%
- Collected and analyzed >3 years of detector operation data to study its stability using Python
- Developed an algorithm to improve the efficiency of reconstructing rare physics data with efficiency > 90%
- Developed a visualization tool for experiment data at Ohio State Physics using Python Web App

LBNL (Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory)

Berkeley, CA 2009 - 2012

Simulated and analyzed femtosecond molecular dynamics using MATLAB

INDEPENDENT PROJECT

TO-BE-ADDED

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data science Machine learning (classification, regression, clustering, feature engineering)

Statistical Methods (Bayesian probability, hypothesis testing, confidence intervals, principal component analysis)

Programming Python (web app development, detector monitoring, scikit-learn, numpy, scipy)

C++ (main language for analysis), MySQL, MATLAB, Mathematica, Linux, LaTeX

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS PRESENTATION

- [1] S. Che, "Signal track reconstruction efficiency in Large radius tracking," ATLAS Experiment, IDTR-2016-006 2016.
- [2] S. Che, N. Pettersson, and J. Duarte, "Development and Performance of algorithms to reconstruct tracks at large radii," ATLAS Experiment, PUB-IDTR-2016-03 2016.
- [3] S. Che, "Development of large radius tracking," in ATLAS Experiment, Chamonix, France, 2015.
- [4] S. Che, "Search for long-lived massive particles with the ATLAS experiment at the LHC," in Graduate Summer Talk, Columbus, Ohio, USA 2016.